<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: information | Drew Sheneman - Software Developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.drewsheneman.com/blog/categories/information/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.drewsheneman.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-21T15:58:51-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.drewsheneman.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Drew Sheneman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Value of Information Privacy]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.drewsheneman.com/blog/2013/06/08/the-value-of-information-privacy/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T12:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.drewsheneman.com/blog/2013/06/08/the-value-of-information-privacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is now a myriad of sources and new information being published at a dizzying rate related to the &lsquo;secret&rsquo; government program:
<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/us-intelligence-mining-data-from-nine-us-internet-companies-in-broad-secret-program/2013/06/06/3a0c0da8-cebf-11e2-8845-d970ccb04497_story.html" target="_blank">PRISM</a>. I swear I&rsquo;ve seen this in a movie before. It is being reported that the NSA has been pulling in data from <a href="http://theweek.com/article/index/245311/sources-nsa-sucks-in-data-from-50-companies" target="_blank">at least 50 companies</a>.</p>

<p>On subjects like these, it is easy for one to feel powerless. It&rsquo;s hard to know which reports are accurate, and if they turn out to be accurate, what action does one take given the new information?
<br/></p>

<h2>Quick thoughts:</h2>

<p><strong>CNN recently proposed </strong><a href="http://money.cnn.com/2013/06/07/technology/security/nsa-data-prism/index.html" target="_blank">scenarios</a> of who had knowledge &lsquo;if&rsquo; the program existed. I personally find it very hard to believe the theory that said companies had no knowledge of information being aquired from their servers. These are massive companies, who, in areas such as software engineering and managing big data are generally hiring those who are the best (or close to the best) at what they do. If it were that easy to aquire some data, everyone would be dropping by for take-out orders.
<br/>
<strong>Our View of Information</strong> I have been beating the private information drum in personal conversations for years. With the rise of social media sites, there has been a shift in the way people generally view personal information. Now we voluntarily post our information, for the world to see. Often times this includes our physical location, on the globe. In reality I think the vast majority of people have no idea where and when that information exchanges hands. This is changing, however.
<br/>
<strong>Take a moment and do this exercise, just from memory:</strong> Try to think of every website that is housing your credit card information in their database, right now. How much of your Facebook profile is shared, vs. friends only, or private? None of this is bad, as long as it is what you choose to do. Issues arise when things are done with our data that we did not choose. However, do you know if you chose it or not? How many of us actually read the fine print? In 2005, a <a href=" http://techtalk.pcpitstop.com/2012/06/12/it-pays-to-read-license-agreements-7-years-later/" target="_blank">software company offered a $1000 prize</a> to anyone who simply read their End-User License Agreement (EULA). It took <strong>five months</strong> for the prize to be awarded.<br/></p>

<h2>Conclusion:</h2>

<p><strong>I am not saying</strong> any of these things are directly related to PRISM. But people taking action to have better guidelines in place is what it will take for things to change, whether it&rsquo;s in the form of votes, or some other method. On the other hand, you could also go ahead and <a href=" http://www.theregister.co.uk/2013/06/08/what_about_a_us_tech_boycott/" target="_blank">boycott the entire US cloud tech</a> &hellip;
<br/>
I don&rsquo;t think I am quite leaping off that ledge &hellip; yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
